# João Paulo Hotequil

Software Developer Santa Catarina, Brazil

hotequil@protonmail.com linkedin.com/in/joao-paulo-hotequil hotequil.tech

#### **DESCRIPTION**

Working in the Information Technology field since 2017, starting with hardware and transitioning to software in 2019. Maintains a consistent study routine, enhancing both soft and hard skills through courses, certifications, projects, books, and lectures. Demonstrates belief in the potential of technology as a tool for decentralization and for providing solutions to customers and companies. Exhibits curiosity, consistency, and focus, exploring various areas to address problems effectively. Prioritizes accessibility, responsiveness, performance, semantics, SEO, usability, testing, YAGNI, KISS, security, and adherence to quality and design standards. Collaborates with teams to create solutions that improve process times, reduce operational costs, facilitate and increase purchases, integrate systems, enable broader device compatibility for applications, document projects and workflows, and conduct application testing.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

## COZ Software Developer | Remote | Denver, Colorado, United States (2024 - present)

Develops decentralized projects and solutions with a focus on blockchain, open source, secure and financial. Utilizes React, TypeScript, Redux, Electron, Tailwind CSS, RushJS, and NodeJS. Implements E2E tests with Playwright and documents data structures. Contributes to Neon Wallet (desktop and mobile), Blockchain Services library. Delivery features like swaps, multi-logins, On/Off ramps, NFT skins, and backup compatibility between platforms. Improves Neo X support, interface flows, Ledger functionality, Flamingo pricing, performance, and builds for Windows, Linux, macOS, Android and iOS.

## PERFORMA\_IT Front-end Developer | Remote | Campinas, São Paulo, Brazil (2021 - 2024)

Specialized in web development for e-commerce, crowdfunding platforms, and financial systems, with expertise in React, Angular, NextJS and TypeScript. Refactored interfaces with modern technologies, integrated ChatGPT and Pix, and contributed to impactful features in Design Systems. Implemented architectural enhancements, security solutions, and file minification pipelines. Participated in Scrum rituals, collaborated with QAs and designers, and delivered high-quality products focused on user experience. Presented workshops on Storybook and Web Accessibility, fostering innovation and team growth.

## VELOW SISTEMAS Front-end Developer | Hybrid | Blumenau, Santa Catarina, Brazil (2019 - 2021)

Worked on creating and maintaining web applications, delivering solutions for e-commerce, social networks, and CRMs. Focused on implementing features for document requests, posts, messages, and notifications. Utilized technologies such as Angular, JavaScript, TypeScript, and RxJS. Contributed to HTTP2 implementation, developed a Design System, and trained new team members. Prioritized customer focus and effective communication with the team.

## **PROJECTS**

## BLOCKCHAIN SERVICES Blockchain | Tools | Financial (2024 - present)

Library for TypeScript applications containing abstracted functionalities to enhance the DX of Electron, Neo 3, Neo Legacy, Ethereum, Neo X, Swaps, and Mnemonics.

# NEON WALLET Blockchain | Financial (2024 - present)

Self-custodial wallet for desktop and mobile devices. Supports Neo 3, Neo Legacy, Ethereum, Neo X and other addresses. Swaps, transfers, dApp connections, custom networks, contacts, hardware wallets, watch accounts, imports and backups are some of the features.

#### **HARVTECH** Agtech | AI | Analysis (2024)

Al solution to predict crop diseases, optimizing field inspections through image analysis.

## TERRA MEETING Fintech | Productivity (2023 - 2024)

Large Brazilian investment firm's system for streamlining client meetings with experts, integrating email, Microsoft Teams, and managing over 200 monthly meetings with scheduling and feedback feature.

## MECHANIZE Tools | Mobile (2023)

Mobile app to connect clients with mechanics via geolocation with features robust security, including Top 10 OWASP practices and encryption.

## **ABACASHI** Fintech | Crowdfunding (2021 - 2023)

Brazilian crowdfunding platform that enables individuals and organizations to create and manage fundraising campaigns for personal projects, social causes, and events in a simple and secure way.

## JOIN IN Social Media | Human Resources (2020 - 2021)

Social media and HR platform that streamlines workforce management with tools like posts, spaces, sub-spaces, internal chat, birthday notifications, surveys, and meal menu.

## **EDUCATION**

## FIAP Bachelor's degree | Information Systems (2021 - 2024)

Gained knowledge in Python, JavaScript, Angular, React, Project Management, UI/UX Design, Web Accessibility, Cloud Computing, and DevOps practices. Completed projects include an Arduino robot, a mobile game for children, a supply chain system (1st place at FIAP Next 2022), an app to call mechanics (2nd place at FIAP Next 2023), and a system to predict agricultural diseases using AI (1st place at FIAP Next 2024).

# **MICROSOFT** Exam 70-480 (2020)

This exam assesses skills in developing web applications using HTML5, JavaScript, and CSS3, including creating user interfaces, managing data, and handling browser interactions.

## **COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS**

Angular and TypeScript, Database SQL, Blockchain, Clean Architecture, Web Accessibility Training, JavaScript, Front-end Developer Training, Reponsive Layouts, EcmaScript and Node IS

## HARD SKILLS

React, Angular, AngularJS, NextJS, ViteJS, Vue, JavaScript, TypeScript, GraphQL, Storybook, RxJS, HTML, CSS, SASS, Styled Components, Prettier, Husky, ESLint, Chakra Ul, Ariakit, Yarn, ES6+, Axios, Animate.css, NodeJS, Netlify and Zustand.

## **SOFT SKILLS**

Communication, continuous improvement, autonomy, proactivity, conflict resolution, collaboration, leadership, active participation, teamwork, task management, adaptability and time management.

## **LANGUAGES**

English and Portuguese.